Guide to the Gail and Stephen Rudin literary autograph collection, 1841-1993.
Rudin, Gail and Stephen autograph collection, 1841-1993
- Frost, Robert: Typed letter to Mr. Mumford. South Shaftesbury, VT., Dec. 12, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  Letter of appreciation.
- Frost, Robert: Autograph letter to Mr. Proctor. South Shaftesbury, VT., Oct. 9, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  Regarding Proetor's Vermont affairs.
- Gardner, Earle Stanley: Typed letter to Angello Hampares. Temecula, CA., Aug. 6, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  Regarding writing experience.
- Gardner, Erle Stanley: Typed letter, Thayer Hobson to Gardner. Ridgefield, CT., Jul. 8, 1954 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  A signed letter of intent confirming his agreement to write 20 book-length manuscripts.
  Rudin # B-48
- Ginsberg, Allen: Autograph letter, Birdbrain to Herbert Mitgang. New York, NY., Oct. 14, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Godden, Rumer: Two typed letters to Wesley Hartley. Sussex; Dumfriesshire, Scotland., May 18, 1974; Aug. 6, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Golden, Harry: Two typed letters, signed postcard to Emolyn Cohn. Charlotte, NC., Jul. 31, 1958 - Sep. 8, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  Regarding Only in America.
- Golding, William: Autographed letter to Huggett. Salisbury, Wiltshire., Oct. 17 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  "Writing is a bitter business". Offers an aspiring writer advice on placing his novella with a publisher.
  Rudin # B-49
- Golding, William: Typed letter to Mr. Norbutt. Salisbury., Apr. 5, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  Regarding what gives literary work lasting importance.
- Gordge, Elizabeth: Autographed letter to William Hartley., Oct. 9 (Box 8, Folder 14A)
- Graves, Robert: Four autograph letters to Peter Dollins. Mallorca, Spain., Mar. 25, 1969 - Mar. 14, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  Advice for writing.
- Graves, Robert: Autograph letter, typed letter by secretary to Mr. Hartley., Nov. 16, 1959; Feb. 2, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  Regarding Graves's career.
- Greene, Graham: Typed letter to Philip Dossé. Antibes., Aug. 1, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  Regarding invitation to nominate reviewer for Greene's book.
- Grey, Dolly: Autograph letter to Boy., Sunday afternoon, no date (Box 2, Folder 23)
  Regarding an affair.
- Grey, Zane: Autograph letter to Miss LaRue. Altadena, CA., May 1, no year (Box 2, Folder 24)
  Letter of thanks, complaint about government.
- Grey, Zane: Autograph letter to Dan. Lackawaxen, PA., May 17, no year (Box 2, Folder 25)
  Regarding travels, problems with editors.
- Grey, Zane: Autograph letter to Dolly. Lackawaxen, PA., Sep. 14, 1905 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  Regarding trip to the woods.
- Grey, Zane: Autograph letter to Dolly. Buckskin Mt., AZ., Apr. 25, 1907 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  Regarding trip to the mountains.
- Grey, Zane: Autograph letter to Dolly. Santa Fe, NM., Thursday, 1908 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  Regarding letter from Dolly.
- Grey, Zane: Autograph letter to Dolly. Catalina Island, CA., Aug. 3, 1918 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  Regarding disagreement.
- Grey, Zane: Autograph draft of Harper Conference., Apr. 9, 1920 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Grey, Zane: Typed letter to Raplh J. Satterlee. Altadena, CA., Nov. 14, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Grey, Zane: Autographed letter. Altadena, CA., December 19, 1934 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  A statement expressing his vehement opposition to "aliens" and to a bill related to gun control.
  Rudin # B-50
- Grey, Zane: Short story titles "On Location" (Box 13, Folder 1A)
  Grey pits real cowboys against the actors that portray them. Story first appeared in the 1978 collection "Buffalo Hunter"
  Rudin # B-50A
- Gustafson, Ralph: Typed letter to Wesley Hartley. Quebec, Canada., Apr. 4, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 15A)
- Haggard, H. Rider: Autographed letter to Barnett Smith. West Kensington., Dec. 29, 1886 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  Assesses his two most famous books, "She" and "King Solomon's Mines".
  Rudin # B-51
- Haggard, H. Rider: Autographed letter to the editor of "The Bookman". Norfolk., Sep. 8, 1908 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  Provides commentary for the "Authors at Work" series.
  Rudin # B-52
- Hale, Edward Everett: Typed letter to Wingate. New York, NY., Sep. 25, 1885 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  Regarding literary criticism.
- Hale, Edward Everett: Autographed letter to Burnside Foster. Roxbury, MA., Dec. 10, 1903 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  Hale describes how "The Man Without A Country" was conceived. Accompanied by a letter written by Burnside Foster referencing the letter written by Hale.
  Rudin # B-52A
- Haley, Alex: Typed letter to Tony Wayman. Rome, NY., Apr. 14, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  Harsh critic Haley minces no words with a budding writer.
  Rudin # B-53
- Haley, Alex: Typed letter to Michael Blow. San Francisco, CA., Jun. 4, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  Regarding Roots.
- Haley, Alex: Typed letter to Michael Blow. San Francisco, CA., Jan. 1, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Haley, Alex: Typed letter to Michael Blow. San Francisco, CA., Nov. 9, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Haley, Alex: Typed letter to Michael Blow. Jamaica, West Indies., Nov. 30, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Hall, Donald: Typed letter to Wesley Hartley. Danbury, NH., Jun. 22, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 19A)
- Hammett, Dashiell: Typed letter to Prudence Whitfield. Aleutians., Aug. 11, 1944 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  Hammett covers a number of subjects including the weather, Dali's "Hidden Faces", and the photography of insects.
  Rudin # B-53A
- Hardy, Thomas: Autograph letter to Alfred Austin. Dorchester., Feb. 6, 1892 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  Regarding Tess of the D'Urbervilles.
- Harris, Joel Chandler: Autographed letter to R.W. Gilder of Century Magazine. Atlanta, GA., May 25, 1879 or 1880 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  Talks of Uncle Remus as well as his article on the rising generation of Negroes in the South.
  Rudin # B-54
- Harte, Bret: Autographed letter to Messrs. Chatto and Windus. Crefeld, Prussia, Feb. 3, 1880 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  A letter to his publisher about a projected new edition of his works.
  Rudin # B-55
- Hawthorne, Nathaniel: Autograph letter to C.W. Webber. Salem, MA., Dec. 14, 1848 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  Regarding written articles. With Hawthorne stamps, photo.
- Heller, Joseph: Typed letter to Vance Morgan; Autograph letter to fan., Oct. 10, 1979; no date (Box 3, Folder 8)
  Regarding Catch-22.
- Hemingway, Ernest: Typed letter to Pete Barrett. San Francisco de Paula, Cuba., Feb. 9, 1951 or Sep. 11, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  Regarding Hemingway's writing policy for TRUE Magazine. With Hemingway stamps, photo, news article.
- Hemingway, Mary: Autograph letter by Ernest Hemingway's wife. San Francisco de Paula, Cuba., Sep. 8, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  Regarding Across the River.
- Hersey, John: Typed letter to Joe Fallis. Key West, FL., Dec. 31, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  Regarding writing of novels.
- Hersey, John: Typed letter to Mr. Fowlers. Vineyard Haven, MA., Apr. 18, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  Regarding becoming a writer.
- Highsmith, Patricia: Typed letter to M. Harrison. Ticino, Switzerland., Jan. 29, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  A letter about her work; what spurred her to start writing; and her favorite books.
  Rudin # B-56
- Holmes, Oliver Wendell: Signed copy of The Last Leaf. Boston, MA. (Book), 1886 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  One of 100 numbered copies.
- Holmes, Oliver Wendell: Autograph letter to Elliot C. Cowdin. Boston, MA., Nov. 14, 1867 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  Regarding annual festival of New England Society.
- Holmes, Oliver Wendell: Autograph letter to Sir. Boston, MA., Oct. 21, 1891 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  Regarding The Last Leaf. With photos, illustration.
- Hughes, Langston: Typed later to Marshall Best, editor of Viking Press. New York, NY, Sep. 7, 1946 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  Hughes writes to Viking Press discussing modern Negro poets and the need for an updated anthology that would include their poetry.
  Rudin # B-57
- Hughes, Langston: Typed letter to Miss Maxon. New York, NY., Mar. 4, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  Regarding character identity. With Hughes stamps and envelope.
- Humphries, Rolfe: Typed letter to Wesley Hartley., Sep. 5, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 24A)
- Hurst, Fannie: Typed letter, autograph note signed "F"., No date (Box 3, Folder 17)
  Regarding advice to beginning writers.
- Huxley, Aldous: Typescript. 155 Westbourne Terrace., No date (Box 3, Folder 18)
  Review of Modern American Poetry.
- Huxley, Aldous: Autograph letter to Mr. Hartley. Los Angeles, CA., Jan. 24, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Irving, Washington: Autograph letter to Rufus W. Griswold. Sunnyside., Oct. 31, 1851 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  Regarding death of James Fenimore Cooper. With author illustration.
- James, Henry: Autographed letter to Frederic MacMillan. Cambridge, MA., Nov. 17, 1881 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  James confesses he is homesick for London.
  Rudin # B-58
- James, Henry: Autographed letter to Mrs. Bigelow. 34 De Vere Gardens., Dec. 14, 1895 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  James writes of many topics including his wish to leave London, his increasing physical difficulty of writing and his great literary ambitions.
  Rudin # B-59
- Jameson, (Margaret) Storm: Typed letter to Wesley Hartley. London, England., Mar. 22, 1961 (Box 8, Folder 26A)
- Johnson, Josephine: Typed letter to Wesley Hartley. Newton, OH., Aug. 12, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Jones, James: Three typed letters to Lafayette Young. Ft. Myers Beach, FL., 1951 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  Among many topics, Jones discusses writing, religion, depression and his weaknesses compared to other writers. Accompanied by a letter to Young from Lowney Handy mentioning Jones, and a typed copy of "The Atlantic's" March 1951 flattering review of "From Here to Eternity".
  Rudin # B-60
- Jones, James: Typed letter to Leonard Lyons. Ft. Myers Beach, FL., Apr. 30, 1952 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  Writes regarding writing a guest column in the "New York Post" about the "two most important days in a first novelist's first publication".
  Rudin # B-61
- Jong, Erica: Typed letter to Dusty Sklar. Weston, CT., Jul. 30, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  Jong addresses the theme of the constant strain between commerically successful and artistically acclaimed books.
  Rudin # B-61A
- Kennedy, Margaret: Typed letter to Wesley Hartley. London, England., Nov. 19, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 29A)
- Kerouac, Jack: Typed letter to Daniel DeSole., Aug. 25, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  Writes of how he does not want to be contacted by anyone so he can get his thoughts down on paper.
  Rudin # B-62
- Kilmer, Joyce: Autograph letter to wife Aline. France., Jan. 24, 1918 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  Regarding money for wife while he is at war
- Kipling, Rudyard: Typed letter to Mr. Heald. Sussex., Sep. 9, 1934 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Kirkwood, James: Eleven typed letters to editors and publicity staff of Little Brown. Los Angeles, CA. New York, NY., Jan. 1960-Jan. 1961 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  File of correspondence relating to the publication of his first book, "There Must Be A Pony!"
  Rudin # B-63
- L'Amour, Louis: Typed postcard to Mr. Judd. New York, NY., No date (Box 3, Folder 24)
- L'Amour, Louis: Typed letter to Evie Landsberg. Includes a photograph of L'Amour given to Evie Landsberg.Beverly Hills, CA., Feb. 8, 1953 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  L'Amour writes a unique and personal "courtship" letter.
  Rudin # B-64
- L'Amour, Louis: Typed letter to Mr. Casey. Los Angeles, CA., Mar. 4, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  Regarding upcoming books, future trips.
- L'Amour, Louis: typed letter to Gary Lorenz., Feb. 11, 1987 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  L'Amour gives advice on writing.
  Rudin # B-64A
- L'Amour, Louis: typed letter to Mr. Juscik, November 24, 1987 (Box 14, Folder 2A)
  …"I doubt if I was ever influenced by any other writer, even when I was beginning.…But I never had any desire to imitate any other writer"…"My only hang-up…is critics: I do not believe any writer should read his reviews or criticisms of his work."... "I also believe that I am only now becoming a good writer." L'Amour closes the letter with comments regarding Van Gogh, Poe, Irving and Whitman, among others.
- L'Amour, Louis: Typed letter to Mr. Montane., Sep. 7, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  Advice for writing short stories.
- Lardner, Ring: Autographed letter to Miss Barnes. East Hampton, Long Island, NY. (Box 9, Folder 3)
  His favorite expression, "How fine it is to be clever".
  Rudin # B-65
- Lardner, Ring: Typed letter to Mr. Kroll. New York, NY., Mar. 24, 1930 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- Lawrence, D.H.: Autograph letter to Mrs. Conway. Questa, NM., Aug. 28, 1925 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  With photos.
- Lawrence, D.H.: Autographed letter to Else Jaffe. Les Diablerets, Vaud, Switzerland., Jan. 31, 1928 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  Discusses his literary work, writes of his reaction to the snows of Switzerland and that he is "sick to death of literature".
  Rudin # B-66
- Lawrence, D.H.: Autographed letter to Mason., February 4, 1928 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  Lawrence details a covert plan to publish an unexpurgated edition of "Lady Chatterly's Lover".
  Rudin # B-66A
- Lawrence, T.E.: Autograph letter to T.C. Griffin. Mount Batten, Plymouth., Apr. 17, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  Regarding years in Middle East, Seven Pillars of Wisdom. Signed "T.E. Shaw".
- Lear, Edward: Autographed letter to Lady Waldegreen [?], Jul. 26, 1877 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  Lear composes an original drawing and limerick.
  Rudin # B-66B
- Lewis, Sinclair: Typed letter to Lloyd Lewis. New York, NY., Feb. 22, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  Regarding Jayhawker, travel plans. With Lewis stamps.
- Lewis, Sinclair: Typed letter to Margaret. New York, NY., Apr. 27, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  Regarding travel plans.
- Lewis, Sinclair: Seven typed letters to and from Lewis, original typescript of Article on Fiction Writing., Aug. 16, 1946 - Sep. 24, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  Regarding Article on Fiction Writing.
- London, Jack: Typed letter to William Teichner. Sonoma, CA., Mar. 6, 1911 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  Regarding prisoners and prisons. With London stamps.
- London, Jack: Typed letter to Ivan T. Dowell. Sonoma, CA., Feb. 2, 1913 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  Advice for writing. With copy of Richard Le Gallienne letter.
- London, Jack: Typed letter to Mr. Koontz. Sonoma Co, CA, Mar. 2, 1913 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  Explains his position on Socialism.
  Rudin # B-67
- Longfellow, Henry Wadsworth: Signed document., Apr. 3, 1860 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  A check-like receipt acknowledging payment of $150 "for copyright on 1000 Hiawatha".
  Rudin # B-68
- Longfellow, Henry Wadsworth: Autograph letter to Mrs. Adams. Cambridge, MA., Apr. 9, 1864 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  Regarding Mrs. Adams's family. With author illustration.
- Longfellow, Henry Wadsworth: Autographed letter addressed to "Dear Sir". Cambridge. Includes copy of signed engraving of Longfellow., Sep. 23, 1880 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  Informing an admirer that the person referred to in the sonnet on the "Churchyard at Tarrytown" is Washington Irving.
  Rudin # B-69
- Longfellow, Henry Wadsworth: Autographed letter to "Dear Madame". Includes signed engraving, 1879. Cambridge., Oct. 9, 1880 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  How Longfellow would pronounce "Hiawatha".
  Rudin # B-70
- Lowell, James Russell: Autographed letter to Rev. Dr. Edward Hale. Cambridge, Mass., Nov. 11, 1890 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  The American Republic will endure "So long as the ideas of its founders continue to be dominant".
  Rudin # B-70A
- Lowell, James Russell: Autograph letter to John Greenleaf Whittier. Cambridge, MA., Aug. 10, 1857 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  Regarding famous poets, contributions to Atlantic Monthly.
- MacLeish, Archibald: Typed letter to Wesley Hartley. Conway, MA., Jul. 27, 1957 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  Responds to a question about the importance of a college education.
  Rudin # B-71
- MacLeish, Archibald: Typed letter to Addison R. Barker. Antigua, West Indies., Jan. 14, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  Regarding Immortal Autumn.
- MacLeish, Archibald: Autograph letter to Genevieve Reall. Conway, MA., Aug. 6, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  Regarding loneliness of writers.
- Mailer, Norman: Typed letter to Louis McKee., Mar. 8, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  Regarding 3 films, Harlot's Ghost, and new book. With signed photo.
- Mailer, Norman: Typed and autographed letters. Probably New York City., 1970 or 1971 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  Two manuscripts - The first manuscript is an annotated typescript of an interview with Mailer in which he surveys his career, his writing, his work habits, and much more. In the second manuscript, Mailer inventories and describes some of the manuscripts and notes he owns for his best works.
  Rudin # B-72
- Mailer, Norman: Typed letter to Martin Levy., Mar. 26, 1997 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  Mailer cites his literary influences.
  Rudin # B-73
- Mann, Thomas: Typed letter to Walter Zivi. Pacific Palisades, CA., Jul. 27, 1943 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  Regarding Death in Venice.
- Mann, Thomas: Typed letter to Camille Honig. Pacific Palisades, CA., Jan. 14, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  Regarding anti-Semitism.
- Markham, Edwin: Autograph letter to Mrs. Washburn. Oakland, CA., Dec. 15, 1898 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  Regarding color. Written by wife.
- Markham, Edwin: Typed letter to Leon Feraru. West New Brighton, NY., Aug. 13, 1917 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  Regarding The Man With The Hoe.
- Markham, Edwin: Typescript of The Man With The Hoe to Leon Fararu., Dec. 31, 1919 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Markham, Edwin: Autograph letter to Leon Fararu. Staten Island, NY., Dec. 31, 1919 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  Revision of The Man With The Hoe.
- Markham, Edwin: Autograph letter to Leon Fararu. West New Brighton, NY., Mar. 1, 1926 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Marsh, John (husband of Margaret Mitchell): Typed manuscript and letter to George B. Dolliver. Atlanta, GA., Jan. 5, 1937 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  The letter describes the genesis of "Gone With the Wind"; "Scarlett O'Hara and all of the other characters in the book are purely fictional"; Mitchell is pleasantly surprised by the reception of the book in the North. The manuscript (unsigned) tells the story of the discovery and the writing of the book.
  Rudin # B-74
- Marshall, Emma: Autograph letter to Sir. Clifton., Feb. 11, 1888 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  Regarding writing.
- Maugham, William Somerset: Autographed letter to Mr. Bafnale. Hotel Mozart., Aug. 7, 1934 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  Maugham expresses his thought process on the necessity of revision, writing and language.
  Rudin # B-75
- Maugham, Somerset: Typed letter to Mr. Payen-Payne. Madras, India, Jan. 31, 1938 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  Regarding critics.
- Maugham, William Somerset: Typed letter to Deane Morrison. Villa Mauresque letterhead., Jul. 23, 1953 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  "What the author has to do is throw himself into the skin of his characters…"
  Rudin # B-76
- Maugham, Somerset: Typed letter to Richard Shone. Ferrat., May 27, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- McCullers, Carson: Typed letter to James Laughlin., Sep. 3, 1959 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  Writes of her writing career, her health and finances and her authorship of and participation in the production of her plays.
  Rudin # B-76A
- Mencken, H.L.: Two typed letters to Joseph Shipley. Baltimore, MD., Jan. 4, 1944; Jan. 8, 1944 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  Regarding origin of "the life of Reilly", encyclopedia preface.
- Michener, James: Signed postard., No date (Box 4, Folder 15)
  Quote from Time magazine article regarding writing.
- Michener, James: Typed letter to Ms. Sklar. St. Michaels, MD., Sep. 1, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  Regarding success in writing.
- Miller, Arthur: Signed playbill. New York, NY., Sep. 14, 1949 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  Death of a Salesman.
- Miller, Author: Letters to and from Saul Rosenzweig. Newspaper clipping. Brooklyn, NY., 1954 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  Correspondence referring to details of "Death of a Salesman" and "The Crucible".
  Rudin # B-77
- Miller, Caroline: Autographed letter to Wesley Hartley., Nov. 18, 1959 (Box 9, Folder 17A)
- Miller, Henry: Typed letter to Rene Fonjallaz. Paris, France., Mar. 15, 1937 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  Miller writes the Swiss author that he is enjoying Fonjallaz's analysis of the American temperment and the American woman.
  Rudin # B-78
- Miller, Henry: Autograph letter to Theodore Schroeder. New York, NY., Apr. 9, 1942 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  Regarding effects of censorship on Miller's books.
- Miller, Henry: Letters to and from Samuel S. Goldberg. Big Sur, CA., Jul. 1944 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  Proposing a way to publish his banned books and a follow-up thank you note stating that, "the Four Freedoms won't help a god damn bit".
  Rudin # B-79
- Miller, Henry: Typed letters to and from Malcolm Cowley. Big Sur, CA., Apr. 21, 1958 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  Miller discusses publication of his banned writings in a large volume of a "Henry Miller Reader". (With two letters of Cowley regarding the Henry Miller Reader)
  Rudin # B-80
- Miller, Henry: Autograph notecard to Roland Fischer., Mar. 19, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Miller, Henry: Autographed letter addressed to "Dear Friend"., Oct. 12, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  "Nobody knows anything about death".
  Rudin # B-81
- Miller, Sue: Signed letters to Jay Neugeboren, fiction editor of "Ploughshares"., ca. 1980 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  Five letters, all pertaining to her first published story, "Expensive Gifts".
  Rudin # B-82
- Milne, A.A.: Autograph letter To The Editor of The Times. New York, NY., No date (Box 4, Folder 20)
  Regarding donations to a charity.
- Milne, A.A.: Autographed letter to Mr. Mayall. Chelsea, NY., Sep. 28 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  A letter regarding a one act play submitted to Milne for publication; "the most difficult piece of property to sell".
  Rudin # B-82A
- Mitchell, Margaret: Typed letter to Mr. Spaulding. Atlanta, GA., Jul. 11, 1936 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  Letter of thanks for a rave review written less than two weeks after the publication of "Gone With the Wind".
  Rudin # B-83
- Mitchell, Margaret: Two typed letters to Dr. Boland. One from Atlanta, GA., Aug. 14, 1936 and May 17, 1949 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  Mitchell accepts a doctor's praise for the medical veracity of "Gone With the Wind". Also included is a letter to the same doctor apologizing for returning one of his books that had become water spotted.
  Rudin # B-84
- Mitchell, Margaret: Typed letter to Mr. Osborne. Atlanta, GA., Nov. 30, 1936 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  "There was nothing of myself or my personal experiences in "Gone With the Wind".
  Rudin # B-85
- Mitchell, Margaret: Typed letter to the editor of "The Lyons Daily News". Atlanta, GA., Nov. 30, 1936 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  Mitchell accepts praise for her work on "Gone With the Wind".
  Rudin # B-85A
- Mitchell, Margaret: Typed letter to Mrs. Guedry. Atlanta, GA., Jan. 21, 1937 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  Mitchell says she does not know what happened to her characters after "Gone With the Wind" ended.
  Rudin # B-86
- Mitchell, Margaret: Typed letter to Miss Martin., Feb. 17, 1937 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  Mitchell explains her "no autograph" policy and admits that she does not own a first edition of "Gone With The Wind".
  Rudin # B-87
- Mitchell, Margaret: Typed letter to Hershel Brickell, July 6, 1937 (Box 14, Folder 3a)
  Mitchell tells Brickell she looks forward to his visit. In a two page postscript she discusses the "bad year" that she has had since the publication of "Gone With the Wind". She mentions imposters, bothersome tourists, her "armor against success" and the lawsuit against "Gone With the Wind".
  Rudin # B-87A
- Mitchell, Margaret: Typed letter to Herschel Brickell. Atlanta, GA., Jun. 28, 1937 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  Regarding Gone With the Wind. Signed "Margaret M."
- Mitchell, Margaret: Typed letter to Herschel Brickell. Atlanta, GA., Aug. 15, 1938 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  Regarding Brickell's leaving of The New York Evening Post. Signed "M."
- Mitchell, Margaret: Typed letter to Ruth Campbell. Atlanta, GA., Aug. 25, 1941 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  Mitchell writes about how she sold the movie rights to "Gone With the Wind" but did not have anything to do with the film.
  Rudin # B-88